改编自《冰与火之歌》
原著 乔治·R·R·马丁
权力的游戏
第八季 第一集
你该庆幸自己走运
You should consider yourself lucky.
至少不会冻掉蛋蛋
At least your balls won't freeze off.
你恨别人讲关于侏儒的笑话
You take great offense at dwarf jokes,
却老拿太监开玩笑  是何道理
but love telling eunuch jokes. Why is that?
因为我有卵蛋  你没有
Because I have balls, and you don't.
我警告过你
I warned you.
北境人不大信得过外人
Northerners don't much trust outsiders.
看看你
Look at you.
都长大成人了
You're a man.
不完全是
Almost.
-艾莉亚呢  -不知道躲在哪儿
- Where's Arya? - Lurking somewhere.
这是坦格利安家族的丹妮莉丝女王
Queen Daenerys of House Targaryen.
这是我妹妹  珊莎·史塔克  临冬城城主
My sister, Sansa Stark, the Lady of Winterfell.
谢谢你请我们到你家来  史塔克小姐
Thank you for inviting us into your home, Lady Stark.
北境正如你哥哥说的那般美丽
The North is as beautiful as your brother claimed,
你也是
as are you.
临冬城是您的了  陛下
Winterfell is yours, Your Grace.
我们没时间客套了
We don't have time for all this.
夜王抓了你的一条龙  它也变成了异类
The Night King has your dragon. He's one of them now.
长城已坍塌
The Wall has fallen,
死人军团正在南下
the dead march south.
我们一接到长城被突破的消息
As soon as we heard about the Wall,
我就下令所有封臣退守临冬城
I called all our banners to retreat to Winterfell.
安柏大人
Lord Umber...
你的人什么时候到
when can we expect your people to arrive?
我们需要更多车马  请小姐允准
We need more horses and wagons, if it please my lady.
大人
And my lord.
女王陛下  失礼了
And my queen. Sorry.
我们会尽量腾出车马支援
You'll have as many as we can spare.
快回最后壁炉城  把你的人带过来
Hurry back to Last Hearth and bring your people here.
我们还得送信给守夜人
We need to send ravens to the Night's Watch as well.
没必要再驻守城堡了
There's no sense in manning the castles anymore.
我们就在这里御敌
We make our stand here.
马上就办  陛下
At once, Your Grace.
"陛下"
"Your Grace."
但你已经不是了  对吧
But you're not. Are you?
你离开临冬城时是国王  但回来时
You left Winterfell a king and came back a--
我也不知道你现在算什么
I'm not sure what you are now.
领主
A lord?
或者什么都不是
Nothing at all?
-这不重要  -不重要
- It's not important. - Not important?
我们拥立你为北境之王
We named you King in the North.
北境之王
King of the North!
是的  小姐
You did, my lady.
那是我莫大的荣幸
It was the honor of my life.
我永远感激你们的信任
I'll always be grateful for your faith.
但我离开临冬城时
But when I left Winterfell,
就说过我们需要盟友  否则必死无疑
I told you we need allies or we will die.
我把盟友带了回来
I have brought those allies home
与我们一同作战
to fight alongside us.
我需要做出选择
I had a choice,
是保住王位  还是保护北境
keep my crown or protect the North.
我选择了北境
I chose the North.
如果这场战争中有谁能活下来
If anyone survives the war to come,
就要感谢琼恩·雪诺
we'll have Jon Snow to thank.
他冒着生命危险证明了威胁真实存在
He risked his life to show us the threat is real.
因为他的勇气
Thanks to his courage,
我们带来了一支
we have brought with us the greatest army
前所未有的大军
the world has ever seen.
我们带来了两头成年巨龙
We have brought two full-grown dragons.
很快  兰尼斯特大军
And soon, the Lannister army
也将北上与我们共同抗敌
will ride north to join our cause.
我知道  我们双方
I know, I know, our people
过去称不上友好
haven't been friends in the past.
但现在  我们必须并肩作战
But we must fight together now...
否则唯有一死
or die.
冒昧地问一句  我们要怎样养活
May I ask, how are we meant to feed
这支有史以来最庞大的军队
the greatest army the world has ever seen?
我分配物资以求挨过寒冬之时
While I ensured our stores would last through winter,
可没算上多斯拉克人
I didn't account for Dothraki,
无垢者和两头成年巨龙
Unsullied and two full-grown dragons.
而且  龙到底吃什么呢
What do dragons eat, anyway?
它们想吃什么就吃什么
Whatever they want.
当心了小伙子们  我们一块也浪费不起
Hey, careful, lads. We need every last bit of it.
抱歉
Sorry 'bout that.
最后几车都在这了
Are these the last of the wagons?
对
Aye.
好  都送到熔炉那去
All right, let's get it all to the forges.
大人
My lord.
夫人
My lady.
告退
临冬城城主
The Lady of Winterfell.
蛮动听的
Has a nice ring to it.
女王之手也不差
So does Hand of the Queen.
我猜取决于谁来当女王
Depending on the queen, I suppose.
我们上次对话还是在乔佛里的婚礼上
Last time we spoke was at Joffrey's wedding.
-可怕的事件  -轰动一时
- Miserable affair. - It had its moments.
我为不辞而别道歉
Apologies for leaving like that.
是啊  我的爱妻在国王殒命当刻失踪
Yes, it was a bit hard to explain
的确难以解释
why my wife fled moments after the king's murder.
我们都没有死掉
We both survived.
低估过你的人很多
Many underestimated you.
如今大半都死了
Most of them are dead now.
得知兰尼斯特大军北上
I'm sure you weren't thrilled to hear
想必你不会太高兴
the Lannister army's marching north.
你惧怕我老姐是有道理的
You have every right to be fearful of my sister.
没人比我更怕她
No one fears her more than I do.
-但我保证  你不会有事  -瑟曦告诉你
- But I promise, you'll be safe-- - Cersei told you her army
她派军队北上是为你们而战
was coming north to fight for you?
没错
She did.
而你相信她
And you believed her?
现在的她有活下去的理由
She has something to live for now.
我相信她有求生的欲望
I believe she wants to survive.
我曾经以为你是世上最聪明的人
I used to think you were the cleverest man alive.
你变矮了
You used to be taller.
你怎么走路没声音
How did you sneak up on me?
你怎么心口挨了刀还没死
How did you survive a knife through the heart?
我死了
I didn't.
你还带着
You still have it.
缝衣针
Needle.
用过吗
Have you ever used it?
一两次
Once or twice.
瓦雷利亚钢
Valyrian steel.
嫉妒了
Jealous?
太重  不适合我
Too heavy for me.
你先前跑去哪了
Where were you before?
不帮我在珊莎面前说句话
I could've used your help with Sansa.
她不喜欢你的女王 是吗
She doesn't like your queen, does she?
珊莎自以为比所有人都聪明
Sansa thinks she's smarter than everyone.
她是我见过的最聪明的人
She's the smartest person I've ever met.
你开始替她说话了
Now you're defending her?
你
You?
我在守护我们的家族
I'm defending our family.
她也是
So is she.
没错
Yeah.
我也是她的家人
I'm her family too.
别忘记了
Don't forget that.
陛下  恐怕我要告诉您一个坏消息
Your Grace, I'm afraid I bring terrible news.
死人军团已经突破了长城
The dead have broken through the Wall.
很好
Good.
何不直接给我个痛快
Why don't you just get it over with and kill me?
我们可是家人啊
But we're family.
世上最后的葛雷乔伊
The last Greyjoys left in the world.
至少是最后两个有种的
The last ones with balls anyway.
要是杀了你
If I kill you...
我跟谁说话去
who can I talk to?
船员都是哑巴
I've got a crew full of mutes.
在海上很寂寞啊
It gets lonely at sea.
我们到君临了吗
Are we in King's Landing?
你站在了必败的一方
You picked the losing side.
那我就带铁舰队换个去处
Then I'll sail the Iron Fleet somewhere else.
但首先  我要上了女王
But first I'm gonna fuck the queen.
两万人  是吗
Twenty-thousand men, is it?
是的  陛下  途中有几人丧生
Yes, Your Grace. A few died in transit.
他们玩骰子出千
They cheated at dice.
也可能是我出千
Or maybe I cheated.
反正有人出千
Someone cheated.
那几个不是什么好战士  对您没损失
They weren't good fighters. You won't miss them.
-马匹呢  -两千匹
- Horses? - Two thousand.
大象呢
And elephants?
没有大象  陛下
Uh, no elephants, Your Grace.
真让人失望
That's disappointing.
我听说黄金团是有大象的
I was told the Golden Company had elephants.
大象是极好的畜牲  陛下
They are excellent beasts, Your Grace,
但不适合漂洋过海
but not well-suited to long sea voyages.
无论如何  你都是
In any event, you are most welcome
君临的座上宾  斯崔克兰团长
here in King's Landing, Captain Strickland.
我们期待为您而战  陛下
We look forward to fighting on your behalf, Your Grace.
我也是座上宾吗
Am I most welcome here?
你是王室的挚友
You are a true friend of the crown
和贵宾
and an honored guest.
很好
Good.
作为挚友和贵宾
As a true friend and an honored guest...
我希望我们能私下谈谈
I was hoping we could talk in private.
战争结束后  我们说好的
After the war. That was our agreement.
战争有时会持续数年
Wars sometimes last years.
你想要个婊子  花钱去买
You want a whore, buy one.
想得到女王
You want a queen...
就要去争取
earn her.
还要怎样
How?
我替她讨还了公道
I've given her justice,
带来一支军队  还有铁舰队
an army and the Iron Fleet,
可她对我爱答不理
yet she gives me no sign of affection.
我的心都快碎了
My heart is nearly broken.
你太无礼了
You're insolent.
我为更微不足道的冒犯处死过人
I've executed men for less.
因为那些人微不足道
They were lesser men.
听说龙烧死了一千兰尼斯特士兵
I hear the dragon burnt up a thousand Lannister men.
烧死了几个我最喜欢的小伙子
Burnt up some of my favorite boys.
-阿奇  是叫这个吧  -还有威廉
- Archie, was it? - And William.
-高大帅气的威廉  -没错  高大帅气的威廉
- Tall handsome William? - Yeah, tall handsome William.
他们说他的残骸一只酒杯就盛得下
They said what's left of him could fit in a wine glass.
我是你们见过的男人里  唯一射中过龙的
I am the only man you ever met who shot a dragon.
-是吗  -差点干掉它
- Did you? - Nearly killed it.
好勇敢
That's brave.
-那个叫埃迪的小子  -那个红毛吗
- That boy Eddie... - The ginger?
就是他  回来时脸都烧掉了
That's him. Came back with his face burnt right off.
他现在没有眼皮了
He's got no eyelids now.
没有眼皮他怎么睡觉呢
How does he sleep with no eyelids?
好了  我们能不讨论该死的龙了吗
All right, can we stop talking about the fucking dragons now?
黑水的波隆爵士
Ser Bronn of the Blackwater.
开什么玩笑
You're kidding me.
抱歉扰您雅兴
Apologies for the interruption,
但女王命我不得延误
but the queen did urge me to hurry.
对不住了  小姐们
Sorry, ladies.
改日吧
Another time perhaps.
您要是寂寞了  记得我偏好年长的先生
You ever get lonely, I am partial to older gentlemen.
可怜的姑娘  梅毒年内就会要了她的命
Poor girl. The pox will take her within the year.
哪一个
Which girl?
女王的弟弟们对你的承诺未能兑现
The queen's brothers made promises to you and broke them.
女王陛下希望纠正他们的错误
Her Grace wants to rectify their mistake.
她曾给我一座城堡  一个妻子
She once gave me a castle and a wife,
转身就"纠正"掉了
then rectified me right out of them.
那是詹姆爵士所为  不是她
That was Ser Jaime's doing, not hers.
瑟曦女王有求于人时
When Queen Cersei wants something,
必是先付酬劳  而且付的是黄金
she pays in advance and in gold.
准确的说是数箱黄金
Several chests of it, in fact.
就在门外的马车上等着你
Waiting for you in a wagon just outside.
所以她想取某人性命  又不能直接派兵
So she wants to murder someone, but she can't send her soldiers.
如果她的目标是龙女王...
If it's the Dragon Queen she's after...
关于坦格利安女孩  女王另有计划
She has other plans for the Targaryen girl.
那就祝她好运了
Yeah, well, good luck with that.
我们女王的弟弟们
Our queen's brothers are unlikely
此次北上  不大可能生还
to survive their Northern adventures.
但万一他们没死...
But in the event that they do...
女王对罪有应得所思甚深
She has a keen sense of poetic justice.
真是一家疯子
That fucking family.
被逐出学城时
When the Citadel expelled me,
我以为自己会在贫困和孤独中死去
I thought I would die poor and alone,
但瑟曦女王以首相之位回报我的辅佐
but in exchange for my service, Queen Cersei made me her Hand.
若有人替她除掉背叛的弟弟们
What would she do for the man
女王会有何奖赏呢
who rids her of her treasonous brothers?
我想要那些战象
I wanted those elephants.
那么
So...
我跟胖子国王比起来怎样
how do I compare to the fat king?
你在侮辱亡夫
You're insulting my late husband?
冒犯到你了吗
Are you offended?
劳勃每晚换一个妓女
Robert had a different whore every night,
可他连鱼水之欢的门道都没摸到过
but he still didn't know his way around a woman's body.
弑君者呢
And the Kingslayer?
你很喜欢生死一线的感觉  是吗
You enjoy risking your neck, don't you?
生活无趣得紧
Life is boring.
你不无趣  这一点我承认
You're not boring, I'll give you that.
我取悦了女王吗
Do I please the queen?
你可能是我见过的最傲慢的人
You might be the most arrogant man I've ever met.
我喜欢
I like that.
但现在我想一个人静静
But now I want to be alone.
我要在你肚子里播种一个王子
I'm going to put a prince in your belly.
攸伦带着全部手下和舰队在君临
Euron can't defend the Iron Islands,
就不可能防守铁群岛
not if he's in King's Landing with all his men and his ships.
我们可以夺回家园
We can take our home back.
丹妮莉丝去了北方
Daenerys went north.
要是他们守不住北境
Daenerys will need somewhere to retreat
总得有个能撤守的地方
if they can't hold the North.
死人去不了的地方
Somewhere the dead can't go.
你是我的女王  我听你差遣
You're my queen. I go where you command.
你想去临冬城
You want to go to Winterfell.
为史塔克家而战
To fight for the Starks.
去吧
Go.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
但还是要杀了那些渣滓
But kill the bastards anyway.
欢迎回来  小姐
Welcome back, my lady.
请跟我来
If you'd follow me...
卡史塔克家
The Karstarks.
家徽不错
One of the better sigils.
至少比洋葱强
Beats an onion, anyway.
无法反驳
Can't argue with that.
不久前  史塔克家和卡史塔克家
Not so long ago, the Starks and the Karstarks
还在战场上互相残杀
were slaughtering each other on the battlefield.
琼恩·雪诺让他们讲和
Jon Snow brought peace to the houses.
我们的女王心怀感激
And our queen is grateful.
她的感激当然好  但那不是我想说的
Her gratitude is lovely, but that's not my point.
北方人效忠的是琼恩·雪诺  不是她
The Northmen are loyal to Jon Snow, not to her.
他们不了解她
They don't know her.
自由民不了解她
The Free Folk don't know her.
我到这里有一阵了  告诉你们
I've been up here a while, and I'm telling you,
他们跟山羊一样顽固
they're stubborn as goats.
想要得到他们的忠诚  只能去争取
You want their loyalty, you have to earn it.
看来你准备献上良策
I sense that you're leading to a proposal.
我建议联姻
A proposal is what I'm proposing.
万一我们真的能击败夜王
On the off chance that we survive the Night King,
或许七国狗屎一样的历史上
what if the Seven Kingdoms,
终于能出现一对像样的统治者
for once in their whole shit history,
女的公正  男的可敬
were ruled by a just woman and an honorable man?
他们确实是一对佳偶
They do make a handsome couple.
你们高估了我们的影响力
You overestimate our influence.
琼恩和丹妮莉丝不会听孤老头子的话
Jon and Daenerys don't want to listen to lonely old men.
我没那么老
I'm not that old.
没他老
Not as old as him.
我们的女王尊重岁月积淀的智慧
Our queen respects the wisdom of age.
那是当然
Of course she does.
尊重是年轻人与我们保持距离的方式
Respect is how the young keep us at a distance,
免得我们让他们想起那令人不快的真相
so we don't remind them of an unpleasant truth.
什么真相
What is that?
事难久长
Nothing lasts.
你妹妹不喜欢我
Your sister doesn't like me.
她不了解你
She doesn't know you.
我不是宽慰你
If it makes you feel any better,
我们小时候  她也不喜欢我
she didn't like me either when we were growing up.
她不必成为我的朋友
She doesn't need to be my friend...
但我是她的女王
but I am her queen.
如果她不能尊重我
If she can't respect me...
今天收获怎样
只有十八只山羊和十一只绵羊
怎么了
What's the matter?
龙吃得太少
The dragons are barely eating.
它们怎么了
What's wrong with them?
它们不喜欢北方
They don't like the North.
上去啊
Go on.
我不知道怎么骑龙
I don't know how to ride a dragon.
没有人知道  骑过才知道
Nobody does. Until they ride a dragon.
要是它不想让我骑怎么办
What if he doesn't want me to?
那我感谢你这些天的陪伴  琼恩·雪诺
Then I've enjoyed your company, Jon Snow.
我该抓着什么
What do I hold onto?
能抓什么就抓什么
Whatever you can.
你害我丧失了骑马的乐趣
You've completely ruined horses for me.
我们可以在这儿躲上一千年
We could stay a thousand years...
没人找得到我们
no one would find us.
那我们可都老得不行了
We'd be pretty old.
对一个南方姑娘来说这里太冷了
It's cold up here for a southern girl.
那就帮你的女王暖暖身子
So keep your queen warm.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
很好
That's good.
-詹德利  -他在
- Gendry? - He's here.
用龙晶锻造这么大的兵刃可不容易
It isn't easy making a blade that big with dragonglass.
你是在夸自己厉害吧
You're saying you're good, is that it?
我只是说这种材料难以...
I'm just saying it's a tricky material to--
知道给野人打兵器的都是什么货色吗
You know who makes weapons for the wildlings?
残废和舔屌的
Cripples and cocksuckers.
-你是哪种  -离他远点
- Which one are you? - Leave him be.
听说你到了这里
I heard you were here.
你丢下我等死
You left me to die.
劫你的财物在先
First I robbed you.
你就是个冷血的小婊子  对吧
You're a cold little bitch, aren't you?
也许这正是你还活着的原因
Guess that's why you're still alive.
你为他打的斧头很不错
That was a nice ax you made for him.
你变厉害了
You've gotten better.
谢谢  你也是
Yeah, thanks. So have you.
我是说  你看上去还不赖
I mean, you look good.
谢谢  你也是
Thanks. So do you.
要不是太冷  在这地方长大也挺不错的
It's not a bad place to grow up, if it wasn't so cold.
那就靠炉子近点
Stay close to that forge, then.
-这是命令吗  史塔克小姐  -别这么叫我
- Is that a command, Lady Stark? - Don't call me that.
如你所愿  小姐
As you wish, milady.
我的所愿是这样的
Here's my wish.
造得出来吗
Can you make it?
你要这种东西做什么
What do you need something like this for?
你能不能造出来
Can you make it or not?
你已经有一把剑了  那是什么
You already have a sword. What's that?
瓦雷利亚钢
It's Valyrian steel.
我就知道你跟别的富家小姐没两样
I always knew you were just another rich girl.
你根本不认识别的富家小姐
You don't know any other rich girls.
请进
Come in.
葛洛佛大人祝我们好运
Lord Glover wishes us good fortune,
他和他的军队只会坐守深林堡
but he's staying in Deepwood Motte with his men.
"葛洛佛家族将站在史塔克家族身后
"House Glover will stand behind House Stark
一千年来一如既往"
as we have for a thousand years."
他是不是这么说的
Isn't that what he said?
他说的是  "我将站在北境之王
"I will stand behind Jon Snow," He said.
琼恩·雪诺的身后"
"The King in the North."
我说过我们需要盟友
I told you we needed allies.
你没说你要放弃北境之王的头衔
You didn't tell me you were going to abandon your crown.
我从未想过称王
I never wanted a crown.
我只想保卫北境
All I wanted was to protect the North.
我带回了两支军队  两头巨龙
I brought two armies home with me, two dragons.
还有一个坦格利安女王
And a Targaryen queen.
你认为没有她  我们能打败死人军团吗
Do you think we can beat the Army of the Dead without her?
我与他们交战过两次  珊莎
I fought them, Sansa. Twice.
你操心的是谁该封什么头衔
You want to worry about who holds what title,
我告诉你这不重要
I'm telling you it doesn't matter.
没有她  我们毫无胜算
Without her, we don't stand a chance.
你对我就没有一点信心吗
Do you have any faith in me at all?
我当然有
You know I do.
她会是一个好女王
She'll be a good queen.
我们所有人的女王
For all of us.
她和她父亲不一样
She's not her father.
是的  她漂亮多了
No, she's much prettier.
你俯首称臣是为了拯救北境
Did you bend the knee to save the North
还是因为你爱她
or because you love her?
你就是那个人吧
So you're the man?
我是哪个人  陛下
Which man am I, Your Grace?
救了乔拉爵士的人  在无人能救他的情况下
The one who saved Ser Jorah when no one else could.
不是不能  是不愿
They could, they just wouldn't.
等我夺回王位  学城也该更新一下气象
I'll have to make some changes in the Citadel when I take my throne.
立大功者需得重赏
A great service merits a great reward.
为您效劳是我的荣幸  陛下
Oh, it's my honor to serve you, Your Grace.
总有什么能让我赏你的吧
Well, there must be something I could give you.
若您不嫌麻烦
If it's not too much trouble,
请赦免我的罪过
I could use a pardon.
你犯了什么罪
For what crime?
我从学城借了几本书
I borrowed a few books from the Citadel.
还有一把剑
And also a sword.
-学城的剑吗  -是我家族的剑
- From the Citadel? - From my family.
在塔利家代代相传
It's been in House Tarly for generations.
论理以后是要归我的
It would've been mine anyway, eventually,
但我父亲另有打算
but my father had other ideas.
不会是蓝道·塔利吧
Not Randyll Tarly?
您认识家父
You know him?
我许诺准许他保留封地和头衔
I offered to let him retain his lands and titles
只要他俯首称臣
if he bent the knee.
但他拒绝了
He refused.
那么
Well...
既然我弟弟做了领主
At least I'll be allowed home again,
至少我可以回家了
now that my brother's the lord.
你弟弟与你父亲持同样立场
Your brother stood with your father.
谢谢您  陛下
Thank you, Your Grace.
谢谢您告诉我
For telling me.
我...
And m--
-我可以...  -当然
- May I...? - Of course.
你在外面做什么
What are you doing out here?
等一位老友
Waiting, for an old friend.
是时候告诉琼恩真相了
It's time to tell Jon the truth.
不  不
No, no.
你是他弟弟  不该由你告诉他吗
You're his brother. Shouldn't you tell him?
我不是他弟弟
I'm not his brother.
他最信赖的人是你
He trusts you more than anyone.
现在时机到了
Now's the time.
山姆
Sam?
抱歉  我知道我不该来这里
I'm sorry, I know I'm not supposed to be down here.
-你是在躲我吗  -当然不是
- Were you hiding from me? - Of course not.
你来临冬城做什么
What are you doing in Winterfell?
难道你已经读完学城所有的书了
Or did you read every book in the Citadel already?
出什么事了
What's wrong?
是吉莉吗  她还好吗
Gilly? Is she all right?
-她很好  -是小山姆吗
- She's good. - Little Sam?
你不知道吗
Don't you know?
知道什么
Know what?
丹妮莉丝
Daenerys...
她处死了我父亲和弟弟
she executed my father and brother.
他们是她的俘虏
They were her prisoners.
她没告诉你
She didn't tell you.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我们得结束这场战争
We need to end this war.
换了你会那样做吗
Would you have done it?
我处死过不服从命令的人
Well, I've executed men who disobeyed me.
你也饶恕过
You've also spared men.
成千上万拒绝下跪的野人
Thousands of wildlings when they refused to kneel.
那时我不是王
I wasn't a king.
你是
But you were.
你一直都是
You've always been.
我放弃了王位  山姆
I gave up my crown, Sam.
我屈膝称臣
I bent the knee.
我不再是北境之王
I'm not King in the North anymore.
我说的不是北境之王
I'm not talking about the King in the North.
我说的是该死的七国之王
I'm talking about the King of the bloody Seven Kingdoms.
布兰和我发现了
Bran and I worked it out.
我找到总主教的日记  布兰...
I had a High Septon's diary. Bran had...
不管布兰怎么知道的
whatever Bran has.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
你母亲
Your mother...
是莱安娜·史塔克
was Lyanna Stark.
你父亲
And your father...
你的生父
your real father
是雷加·坦格利安
was Rhaegar Targaryen.
你从来都不是私生子
You've never been a bastard.
你是伊耿·坦格利安  铁王座真正的继承人
You're Aegon Targaryen, true heir to the Iron Throne.
我很遗憾  我知道你一时很难接受
I'm sorry, I know it's a lot to take in.
我父亲是我认识的最讲荣誉的人
My father was the most honorable man I ever met.
你的意思是他骗了我一辈子
You're saying he lied to me all my life.
不
No.
你父亲  好吧  奈德·史塔克
Your father-- Well, Ned Stark.
他对你母亲发誓永远保护你
He promised your mother he'd always protect you.
他做到了  劳勃要是知道了就会杀了你
And he did. Robert would have murdered you if he knew.
你是名正言顺的国王
You're the true king.
伊耿·坦格利安六世
Aegon Targaryen, Sixth of His Name,
全境守护者  等等等等
Protector of the Realm, all of it.
-丹妮莉丝是我们的女王  -她不该是女王
- Daenerys is our queen. - She shouldn't be.
-这是叛国  -这是事实
- That's treason. - It's the truth.
你为了拯救百姓放弃王位
You gave up your crown to save your people.
她愿意做出同样的选择吗
Would she do the same?
退后  他有蓝眼睛
Stay back, he's got blue eyes!
我一直都有蓝眼睛
I've always had blue eyes!
你找到什么人了吗
Did you find anyone?
安柏家的小子
The Umber boy.
这是信息
It's a message.
夜王留下来的
From the Night King.
他的大军在我们和临冬城之间  我们没有马
His army's between us and Winterfell. We're on foot.
我们是从黑城堡骑马来的
We rode down from Castle Black.
我们可以快马加鞭
We can double up on the horses.
只要马不跑死  我们能抢在死人前面
If the horses last, we'll get there before the dead.
我们只能指望先到的不是夜王了
We just have to hope the Night King doesn't come first.
继续  直走
Keep moving! Straight up!
跟紧了  别掉队
Stay together! Don't fall behind!